Fong Chee Hoon

No.108, Jalan Kerongsang 6,

Bandar Puteri Klang,

41200 Klang, Selangor Darul Ehsan

Tel: 03-51661006 (Home),016- 2021815 (H/P) Email: mas.fong@gmail.com



Executive Summary

I have about 10 years working experience majority in telecommunications industry and consumer electronics industry with exposure across few areas including brand strategy planning, trade marketing, event marketing & management as well as public relation.

I start off my career in a PR firm Essence Communications as PR & Event coordinator to handle all clients servicing on PR & Corporate event planning and management.

Subsequently I worked with DiGi Telecommunications as Trade Marketing Associate, taking care of the point of sales material & promotion items budget, production & distribution and also trade related branding activities such as outdoor signage & shop display. Ensuring all the POSM is distributed on time to the market to push the product sales.

My next career move was Sharp Electronics (M) Sdn. Bhd. as Assistant Manager, Brand Strategy Division for growing market, taking the role of handling brand strategy planning in Asia Pacific region on the corporate branding and master product branding. Assisted by 2 in house designer, handle all the ATL media planning and production work with media agency on the ATL media materials including TV commercial, radio commercial, print advertisement and also BTL advertising and promotion materials. Also handle to develop and monitor the social media platform such as Facebook, Youtube Advertising, Website Portal & Campaign as well as search engine optimization.

I am currently with Electrolux Home Appliances Sdn. Bhd. as Marketing Communications Manager, my role will be handling all marketing related portfolio as in Marketing Communication, Public Relation, Branding, Advertising & Promotion as well as Event Management. I was also managing the digital advertising and social media platform such as Facebook, Youtube, Homepage for the company. I have 2 sub-ordinates that one helping me to handle the digital media. Another person half assisting me on marketing related work and another half handling product marketing portfolio.

I am well versed in various kind of PC software application such as Microsoft office and some creative development tools.

At the same time, I am also well versed in English, Bahasa Malaysia & Chinese (include Mandarin, Cantonese and Hokkien).

Working Experience

Marketing Communications Manager Electrolux Home Appliances Sdn. Bhd. – Marketing Department (June 2015 – Current), Monthly Salary – RM7450 **Job responsibilities:** 360° marketing strategy planning and execution for corporate branding and each product category. Managing the marketing job scope including A&P, Brand Strategy and Communications, Public Relation, Media planning and media buy and as well as event and sponsorship for special project. Also working with in house designer and creative agency on all ATL materials and BTL materials.

Project involved as Marketing Communications Manager

- 1. Electrolux Inspiration range product magazine advertising
- 2. I Love Electrolux TVC Campaign with Astro
- 3. 2016 New Marketing Concept
- 4. Digital Media Transformation
- 5. Warehouse Sales 2015 & 2016
- 6. Cooking Class
- 7. Singapore Family Sales

Asst Manager, Brand Strategy Growing Markets Sharp Electronics (M) Sdn. Bhd. – Brand Strategy Group (Nov 2011 – April 2015), Monthly Salary – RM5510 **Job responsibilities:** Brand strategy planning in ASEAN region for Sharp Corporation on the product branding and corporate branding. Handle ATL media planning with monitoring the regional branding activities from Sharp sales subsidiaries. Work with media agency on the ATL media materials including TV commercial, radio commercial, print advertising visual and also below the line advertising materials. Manage the special project sponsorship for specific country in the region of ASEAN in terms of brand strategy. Involve in TV commercial shooting for ASEAN region.

Project Involved as Asst Manager, Brand Strategy Growing Markets

- 1. Sharp AQUOS free style soccer TV commercial campaign(Philipines, Malaysia, Indonesia)
- 2. Sharp Plasmacluster Product TV commercial campaign (Philipines, Malaysia, Indonesia)
- 3. Sharp 100th Years Anniversary Campaign (ASEAN Region)
- 4. Sharp Euro 2012 Sponsorship Campaign (ASEAN Region)
- 5. Living in Sharp Life website and branding campaign
- 6. Sharp Plasmacluster infomercial TVCM
- 7. SharpAQUOSTVCM
- **c.** Senior Executive, Event Management Spice CSL International (M) Sdn. Bhd. Sales & Marketing Department (Dec 2010 Nov 2011), Monthly Salary RM 4200

Job responsibilities: Event planning and event management. Handle the whole event flow from the setup until the dismantling. Supervise the flow of the event operation plus arrange the promotions mechanics. Handle event setup concept and the event props.

Project Involved as Senior Executive, Event Management

- 1. PC Fair 2011
- 2. CSL Dealer Gathering 2011
- 3. MID In Shop Roadshow
- 4. ShoppingComplexRoadshow
- 5. Gary Chaw Concert Presenter
- 6. Miss Malaysia Pageant 2011 Presenter
- 7. Transformer 3 Roadshow
- **d.** Trade Marketing Associate in DiGi Telecommunications Sales & Distribution (Dec 2006 Aug 2010), Monthly Salary RM 3077

Job responsibilities: Distribution and promotional premium items planning. Take care of the point of sales materials production and timeline. Manage the costing and budget for the Point of sales materials of the entire acquisition. Assign printer or supplier for the POSM materials and event & promotion premium items. Manage the signage and brand appearance in the market. Deal with agency on the FA ready date and handling special point of sales materials in the market for dealer. Manage the branding CI to be appearance on the materials to be distributed out to market, and also find out the best materials method to roll out to market to push the product sales. Study and understand the competitor product and activity in order to propose reaction to management.

Project Involve as Trade Marketing Associate

- 1. 8th DiGi Gold Dealer Dinner January 2007
- 2. DiGi Mission Impossible 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 & 10
- 3. 9th DiGi Gold Dealer Dinner July 2007

- 4. DiGi Postpaid 1 Plan Revamp Acquisition
- 5. DiGi Postpaid 1 Plan Family Lauching
- 6. DiGi Prepaid 50/50 Reload Contest Launching
- 7. DiGi Prepaid New 1 Low Flat Rate 36sen Revamp Acquisition
- 8. DiGi Friends & Family Plus Acquisition
- 9. DiGi Fu Yoh Acquisition
- 10. DiGi Postpaid Samsung & Sony Ericsson Phone Promo Launching
- 11.10th Gold Dealer Dinner January 2008.
- 12.DiGi Free 200 SMS Chinese New Year promo
- 13.DiGi YCF Standee Promo Project
- 14.DiGi Prepaid Bus Stop Signage Installation
- 15.DiGi Cakap Cakap Migrant Promo
- 16.DiGi Postpaid Mother's Day Family Basic Plan Promo
- 17.DiGi Prepaid Euro FNF 11 Promo
- 18.DiGi Eastern Pek Senang Launching
- 19.DiGi Klang Valley Mass Attack Ground Control (Seremban, Subang, Port Klang, Petaling Java)
- 20.DiGi Postpaid I love Saving Launching
- 21.DiGi Mobile Number Portability (MNP) Launching
- 22.DiGi Prepaid I Like Prepaid Revamp Launching
- 23.DiGi Postpaid DG30 Plan Launch
- 24.DiGi Prepaid Hit RM1 Launch
- 25. Prepaid Easy Campaign Launch
- 26.DiGi Internet Revamp Promo
- 27.DiGi BlackBerry Smart Plan Promo
- 28.DiGi Postpaid November Revamp
- 29. East Coast Happy New Launch
- 30.DiGi Bulk SMS Promo Launch
- **e.** Event Coordinator in Essence Communications Event Division (Oct 2005 July 2006), Monthly Salary RM1800
- **Job responsibilities:** Event planning and event management. Come out with a proposal for the client to approve on the budget. Adjust the costing according to the client request and also according to the client budget. Deal with the supplier to make sure we get the things above the value we had paid.

Project Involved as Event Coordinator:

- 1. Siemens Celcom Futsal Challenge
- 2. Siemens Run 2006 Press Conference
- 3. Siemens Communications F1 Party
- 4. Siemens Power Breakfast 2005 & 2006
- 5. Siemens DiGi Edge Showcase Roadshow
- 6. Siemens Digital Lifestyle Roadshow
- 7. Siemens Digital Lifestyle Roadshow Launch
- 8. Siemens A & D Social Night
- 9. Siemens Day 2005

- 10. Siemens Golf Classic 2005 & 2006
- 11. Siemens Scholastic Award 2005
- 12. Siemens CRM Go-Live Launch 2006
- 13. Siemens Go Greener Day
- 14. Siemens Breakfast Chat
- 15.German Leadership Network Launch
- 16.Oktoberfest 2005
- **f.** PR Coordinator in Essence Communications PR Division (May 2005 Oct 2005), Monthly Salary RM 1800
- **Job responsibilities:** Produce monthly PR Report for the client to aware of the market trend and also the development of their brand name in the market. Organize conference and launch event for the client. Monitoring press media and update the client on the latest market news. Planning yearly activities for client to build the brand awareness among the public.

Project Involved as PR Coordinator:

- 1. YasminTakeChargeCampaign
- 2. Women's Healthcare Public Forum
- 3. Yasmin Mother's Day Crossword Puzzle Competition
- 4. DiGi Siemens Mini Futsal Tournament
- 5. Siemens Maxis 3G Signing Press Conference
- 6. 2nd Siemens Maxis Golf Challenge
- 7. NAGCM & Neslac Music Workshop
- 8. Neslac Science Workshop
- 9. DHL Service Point Launch
- **g.** Industrial Training in a PR Agency Essence Communications PR Division Job responsibilities: Produce monthly PR Report for the client to aware of the market trend and also the development of their brand name in the market. Organize conference and launch event for the client. Monitoring press media and update the client on the latest market news.

Education

Private University: Multimedia University

2001 - 2005

Major: Bachelor of Multimedia (Hons) Media Innovation and Management CGPA:

3.14

Current Salary: RM 7450

Expected Salary: RM 9500 (Negotiable)

Language: BahasaMalaysia

English

Chinese (include Mandarin, Cantonese and Hokkien)

<u>Skill</u>

Well verse in various kinds of PC software applications such as Microsoft office and some creative development tools. Has total experience of one and half years in Public Relation, 3 years in Event Management, 5 years in Brand Strategy Planning and 4 and half years in Trade Marketing. I have good planning, negotiation, project management and presentation skill as well as great communications skill. I am familiar with presentation for internal and external in terms of present new concept idea or reporting.

Personality

I am Fong Chee Hoon, 34years old, young, active, energetic, creative and ambitious person experience in various kind of industry looking for a challenging job opportunity where the organization offers promising future and a personal growth prospects. In return, I am willing to offer my hundred percent – sincere efforts and professional performances as my contribution towards company's overall progress. Besides that, I am able to cooperate and communicate with any level of peoples very well. I am hardworking and have great interpersonal. Also, I am a fast learner and willing to learn new things and accept opinion from others. I am always be able to think out of the box to create new ideas to drive the strategy to achieve company target.

Offer me the opportunity to meet you personally and I can promise you, I won't let you down.

Reference

Name: Che Ruby Mohamed

Company: Celcom

Position: Head of Trade Marketing

Contact no.: 019-219 3000 Email: ruby@celcom.com.my

Name: Bruce Teh Company: BH Petrol

Position: Purchasing Manager Contact no: 016-666 0247